export const data = [
    {
      question: "Who is know as the father of computers??",
      option1: "Dennis Ritchie",
      option2: "Charles Babbage",
      option3: "Ken Thompson",
      option4: "Charlie Babbage",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "Which supercomputer is introduced by the Indian Scientist?",
      option1: "Super 301",
      option2: "Param",
      option3: "CRAY YMP",
      option4: "Compaq Presario",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "The IC chips used in computers are made up of?",
      option1: "Lead",
      option2: "Silicon",
      option3: "Chromium",
      option4: "Gold",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "Who designed the Qwerty keyboard?",
      option1: "Charles Babbage",
      option2: "Christopher Latham Sholes",
      option3: "Ken Thompson",
      option4: "Charlie Babbage",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "Which language among the following is used by Apple computers?",
      option1: "Assembly Language",
      option2: "Machine Language",
      option3: "Swift Language",
      option4: "Functional Programming Language",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "What is the name of the first general-purpose electronic computer?",
      option1: "UNIVAC",
      option2: "EDVAC",
      option3: "MAC",
      option4: "ADVAC",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Who is deemed as the Father of Artificial Intelligence?",
      option1: "Elon Mask",
      option2: "Leo Forest",
      option3: "John McCarthy",
      option4: "JP Eckert",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "How can we measure the quality of a printer?",
      option1: "By using Words per Strike",
      option2: "By using Dots per Inch",
      option3: "By using Lines per Strike",
      option4: "By using Dots per Strike",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "What is the full form of IBM?",
      option1: "International Backlog Machine",
      option2: "Integral Business Machine",
      option3: "International Business Mechanism",
      option4: "International Business Machine",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the options mentioned below is not a programming language?",
      option1: "BASIC",
      option2: "JAVA",
      option3: "BNF",
      option4: "FORTRAN",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Who is deemed as the Father of Supercomputing?",
      option1: "David J.Brown",
      option2: "Gene Amdahl",
      option3: "Adam Dunkels",
      option4: "Seymour Cray",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "When was NASSCOM (National Association of Software and Services Companies) established?",
      option1: "1988",
      option2: "1997",
      option3: "1993",
      option4: "1882",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Which one is the first high-level programming language?",
      option1: "C",
      option2: "COBOL",
      option3: "FORTRAN",
      option4: "C++",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Which one is the first-word processor application?",
      option1: "MS Word",
      option2: "Apple I Work",
      option3: "WordStar",
      option4: "Sun StartOffice",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "What does the command prompt use?",
      option1: "CLI(Command Line Interface)",
      option2: "GUI(Graphical User Interface)",
      option3: "Text User Interface TUI",
      option4: "None of the above",
      ans: 1,
    }
  ];